

Ranchi, Jharkhand

□ (+91) 821-009-8916 | 🗷 amitsin6h@gmail.com | 🖸 amitsin6h | 🚵 amitsin6h | 🛅 amitsin6h

Summary_

Self taught computer programmer. Currently Founder, Fullstack Developer & DevOps in start-up Devconsole. I have 2.5+ years experience specializing in backend/infrastructure, web development and security. I also write my own programming tutorials at C-SharpCorner. Super nerd who loves Linux and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Wor**k Experience**_____

Feelin Ranchi, Jharkhand

FOUNDER, FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DEVOPS

Jan. 2019 - PRESENT

- · Developed the complete UI/UX of the app using React Native, Redux, Apollo, Graphql and other third party libraries
- Designed the product website using MERN stack
- Updating the REST API backend design using Apollo, Graphql, Express
- Implemented RESTful API server using ExpressJS and NodeJS.
- Implemented API request validation using JsonWebtoken
- Implemented API caching technique to handle requests
- Implemented Flynn PaaS to manage product on production
- Designed advance MongoDB schema for the complete product
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, Flynn PaaS.

GirlScript Summer of Code

India

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR Mar. 2019 - May 2019

 MEVN CLI: A CLI tool for getting started with the MEVN stack. It offers a super simple boilerplate template and additional utilities for building a MEVN stack based webapp.

cloudyBoss Sydney, Australia (Remote)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Sep. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- · Cloud programming (both client and server-side)
- Application Programming Interfaces
- · Agile methodologies and UML
- · Object Oriented Programming, UI/UX design

Devconsole Ranchi, Jharkhand

FOUNDER, FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DEVOPS

Jan 2018 - PRESENT

- Developed the complete UI/UX of the product
- · Created REST API server using ExpressJS and NodeJS.
- Implemented API request validation using Jsonwebtoken
- Designed MongoDB schema for the complete product
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, Flynn PaaS

LinuxWorld Informatics Pvt Ltd

Jaipur, Rajasthan

INTERN

Jun 2018 – July 2018

- Project: Al Monkey an Al based web browser. This project aims to provide consultancy to user based on their search result in the browser.
- SAAS(Software As A Service) A one-click implementation was achieved which provided the clients Firefox browser and VLC media player software's on their system's from DOCKERS running on the cloud server.
- STAAS(Storage As A Service)

Block Storage - In Block storage we used ISCSI Protocol to provide clients with block storage available at the cloud to be used at the client

Object Storage - In Object storage, using NFS and SSHFS Protocol to provide user fixed storage over cloud.

- · CAAS(Container As A Service) A one-click launch, starting, stopping and removing and providing the terminal of docker container was
- PAAS(Platform As A Service) A one-click launch of python platform was provided for clients where they can code as they wish.
- Hadoop A CGI based web portal was developed for a one click setup of hdfs and map reduce cluster depending on the requirements of the client per se, the size of the cluster required, and the number of processors required for the big data analysis.
- Machine Learning The web service for the client was secured by Face recognition using machine learning and also include parts of speech recognition using python modules. IMAGE PROCESSING constitutes a large portion of the security aspect of the service.
- Ansible The entire configuration requirement of the project was met by creation of ANSIBLE playbooks for both client and the cloud.
- · Dockers For the safe and secure single client based service production, most of the services were provided through dockers only.

Genesis DigisecRanchi, Jharkhand

• Developed complete SEO and Google analytics for a wordpress website.

- Also worked in UI/UX of that wordpress website
- Suggested online marketing strategy for promotion of the website

Cyber Peace FoundationRanchi, Jharkhand

Jr. Researcher

· Worked in Indian Honeynet Project

- Developed website and web application
- Developed widows and linux software using NodeWebkit

ResultsTrack Pvt. Ltd

Ranchi, Jharkhand

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nov 2016 – Feb 2017

Aug 2016 - Nov 2016

Jan 2018 – Feb 2018

Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

- · Worked in Data Visualization projects and Data Analysis
- · Developed android app to collect survey in offline mode and automatically gets updated whenever the internet was connected
- · Worked in websites and web application projects

NathCorp Inc.

Ranchi, Jharkhand

INTERN

- · Worked in Data Visualization projects and Data Analysis
- Developed dynamic graphs and maps using php and third party javascript library

Education.

Institute of Management Studies

Ranchi, Jharkhand

M.B.A 2019 - 2021

- Information Technology
- Selected for "Business English for Young Professional Workshop" conducted by U.S Embassy

Y Combinator Startup School

Remote

2019

2015

STARTUP AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP

• Y Combinator Startup School is a 10-weeks course hosted by Silicon Valley's premier startup accelerator Y Combinator.

Marwari College, Ranchi

Ranchi, Jharkhand

B.B.A

2015 - 2018

• Marketing Hons

Central Academy, Bariatu

Ranchi, Jharkhand

AISSCE

Commerce

Army Public School, Ranchi

Ranchi, Jharkhand

AISSE

20

• Completed 2 years (2010-2012) in Army wing 3JH BN NCC Ranchi as Lance Corporal/ Corporal. Also passed 'A' Certificate examination held in 2012 under the authority of Ministry of Defence, Government of India.

Hackathons & Achievements

- 2020 eLife Innovation Leader, eLife
- 2019 Intel Edge AI Scholar, Udacity
- 2018 OpenTechNights Winner, FOSSASIA
- 2017 **Quality Assurance Contributor**, Mozilla
- 2017 **First**, Hackathon De Corps 2017
- 2016 **Second**, UTKRAANTI'16 with Padarth'16 IIT Bombay
- 2016 **ASSOCIATE TRAINER**, App Development Training for Nepalese
- 2015 **Top 10**, App Hackathon 2015 (Gov. of Jharkhand)

Certifications_

2019cloudyBoss accreditation cBX82 Technology,cloudyBoss2017Red Hat Certified System Administrator,Red Hat, Inc.2017Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation,Red Hat, Inc.2016Intro to Python for Data Science Course,DataCamp

FEBRUARY 13, 2020 AMIT KUMAR SINGH · RESUME 2

Volunteer_

 OpenGenus
 India

 Contributor
 2017

CONTRIBUTOR

• Code contribution for different algorithms in Cosmos. Suggested idea and worked on mockup of Cosmos Code Compiler (C3).

PyCon India 2017 India

Contributor

- Working with web development team for fixing the web related issues.
- · Volunteered for Machine Learning Fruitful and Fun using Orange

PyConf Hyderabad 2017 India

CONTRIBUTOR 2017

- Working with web development team for code contribution to website
- · Responsible for fixing the web related issues in github

HackClub Ranchi, Jharkhand

HackClub Leader April 2016 - April 2017

- Responsible for building local community of developers in college and universities
- Organizing tech events and Club meet-ups

Mozilla India

CONTRIBUTOR 2015 - PRESENT

- Responsible for event organizing, meet-ups for community
- Quality Assurance contributor from Mozilla India team
- Create FOSS Awareness in colleges, schools and universities

National Anti-Hacking Group

Ranchi, Jharkhand

2017

CONTRIBUTOR 2015 - PRESENT

- · Awareness Campaigning
- Code contribution

Pro**jects**

Feelin

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT

· Social app where people can share their feelings publicly or anonymously

Devconsole

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT

• Online student and startup platform

AI Monkey

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT

· AI based web browser which consult user based on their search query.

MozCode Paste

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT

· MozCode Paste, project which was shortlisted for Mozilla Pulse. This project aims to paste code, share code and get the code reviewed.

Air Notes

ANDROID DEVELOPMENT

· Notes app in which notes can be synced online

UC News Clone

ANDROID DEVELOPMENT

· UC News Clone app which shows news from difrrent news website.

Django Twitter

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT

• Beta twitter clone using python and django web framework

Ski**lls**_

- Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, JS, JQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, SocketIO
- Back-End: NodeJS, GraphQL, Apollo, Python, PHP, SocketIO

• Web Server: Nginx, Apache

• Mobile App: React-Native, Android Studio, Ionic,

Desktop App: NW.jsDatabase: MySQL, NoSql

• Web Framework: MERN Stack, MEAN Stack, Django, Flask, Codelgniter, LAMP

• Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, PHP

• Version Control Tools: Git, Github, Bitbucket

PaaS: CloudJiffy, Dokku, FlynnDevOps: Ansible, Splunk

• Big Data: Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Splunk

• Data Analysis: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plottly

• Others: Web Security, OWASP TOP 10, Networking, Web Scrapping, Linux, Quality Assurance, Data Mining